Fernando Ascencio

MOBILE DEVELOPER

Portfolio



fhazel.com.mx

Contact



+52 3334953311



fernandohazel1@gmail.com



Guadalajara, Mexico, Zapopan Jal.



<u>fernandohab</u>



<u>FernandoHazel</u>

Languages

Spanish: English: Native Advanced

Skills

Swift/SwiftUI/UIKit Git

Unity Scrum

Node Js Firebase

NET MAUI

C# Express js

JavaScript AWS

Kotlin Azure

Jetpack Compose Google Cloud

HTML / CSS/ JS SQL

Education

Bachelor in Digital Animation Tecnológico de Monterrey | January 2018 - December 2022

Videogame Developer Diploma Tec De Monterrey | February 2021 - May 2021

Full Stack Developer Diploma Digital House | April 2021 - August 2021

Unity Programmer Diploma Unity Technologies | November 2022

About me

I am a 4 years experience developer which have worked in videogames, AR and mobile apps. My stack is Kotlin, Swif and Unity but I have touched some others like Net MAUI, Nodejs and SQL. My passion is to develop apps and mobile games.

Professional Experience

iOS Developer

Bradescard | From March 2024 to the present

I working in a Mexican bank called Bradescard as iOS developer, Bradescard works with many partners like C&A, Cuidado con el perro, Bodega Aurrera, Shasa and Promoda. I'm in charge of creating new functionalities, bug fixes and review others team members work for the iOS app. My responshabilities are:

- Work in a large iOS development team to create new functionalities using scrum methodology.
- Created new functionalities and bug fixes with swiftUI, UIKit and .xib files for more than a million users.
- Collaborated with product, fraud, finance and marketing team to ensure quality.
- Created a black list functionality to prevent fraud witch permited to reach
 the service payment amount from \$100MXN to a non limit threashold which
 increased the bussiness profit and made the app safer.
- Implemented an option to unlock the payment card during the service payment workflow wich increased bussines profit because before many users where trying to pay with a blocked card, they could't and each try had a cost for the company.
- Consume API rest services from AWS microservices.
- Cached images and text from a media manager called Magnolia using NSCache
- Worked with analytics, crashlytics, remote config and app distribution with firebase to ensure the app was working well for our 7,000 users connected at the same time evey day.
- Gived support to user accounts in postgres and SQL Server databases.
- Ensured quality by an CI/DC pipeline in azure made with terraform.
- Managed App Store development and deployment with certificates, profiles and devices in App Store Connect to ensure all the development team can work correctly and the final users gets the updates.
- Solved Apple reviews problems to make sure our 2 million users gets the updates.

AR and Mobile Developer

GSN Qro. Qro | November 2022 - May 2023

I worked at an XR company and was in charge of creating a hololens AR and a mobile experience of Grupo Bimbo and Silberhorn as well as a NET MAUI internal Managment Tool.

- Collaborated with product team to implement specifications using C#
- Consumed REST APIs perfing CRUD operations to display, modify and store data in JSON format.
- Created a responsive UI and UX experience for IOS and Android.
- Used Git to ensure a better and safer workflow with the rest of the team.
- Tested and fixed bugs to ensure hight quality.
- Created internal company apps for Grupo Bimbo, Ferromex and Silberhorn with unity for staff training and managment wich resulted in a more efficient and easy way to train staff and avoid dangerous mistakes.
- Created an internal app with .NET MAUI for employees which improved the internal company efficiency and comunication.
- I have also developed freelance apps like the one I created for a bar using .NET MAUI so bar clients can buy happy hours by an app.
- I developed a mobile app for a mexican pro football american team wich has more than 20K fan using Kotlin, SwiftUI, Firebase and Google Cloud services

Mobile Game Developer

One Simple Game Guadalajara. JAL | February 2022 - August 2022 | worked as an intern in a mobile game studio.

- Collaborated with designers to implement new mechanics using C# applying OOP and design patterns
- Created a fully responsive UI an UX experience with Unity canvas
- Documented code for better workflow and understanding
- Tested and fixed bugs resulting in a 90% reduction of bugs
- Added analytics SDK to track the user actions during the game session.
- Collaborated with artist, game designers and marketing staff by scrum methodology.
- Used Git to ensure version control and safer workflow with the development team.

Programming Teacher

Fhazel Solutions Tech | From December 2021 to present (on free time)

I like to learn while I teach, so I give personalized classes and I have a YouTube channel.

- Teached an eanglish teacher to create a Nodejs app wich connects students and professors in China, this project helped the teacher to get her first developer job.
- Teached a doctor to develop a unity app for neonatologists wich helped a lot of doctors to follow all the necessary steps and generate a report during a birth, which improved the successful birth rate in the Sierra Taraumara.
- I love to create youtube videos about how videogames and apps are creaded without talking about hard programming topics so anyone can understand. My channel has 2,500 subscribers and my most succesfull video has 30k views.

Project Manager

Tec de Monterrey and my own | From January 2021 to present

During school I was the project manager of many project as 2 videogames and 2 spots for Cartoon Network and Nickelodeon,

- I was in charge of manage two teams of 5 persons to develop one videogame each one.
- I was the producer of a 20 members team and we were in charge of producing a 2-3 minutes spot for Cartoon Network using animation pipline and tools like Maya, Adobe Premiere, Adobe ilustrator, Toom boom Harmony and Trello with scrum methodology.
- I was the producer of a 20 members team and we were in charge of producing a 2-3 minutes spot for Nickelodeon using animation pipline and tools like Maya, Adobe Premiere and Trello with scrum methodology.